

1000 Felipe Bender St Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil CEP 95660-000 +55 (51) 9 9295 7194 www.quadrat.bio.br biofsdev@gmail.com

Fernando Soares

Senior conservation biologist, science driven, socioenvironmental project developer

PROFILE

For the past 11 years I have been the lead biologist at Tres Coroas townhall, overseeing all legislation and documentation related to environmental licenses across all industry, mining, infrastructure, and service sectors. Since 1986 I have been involved in I.T., learning and contributing to the field of science education and biodiversity conservation. Particularly fond of Python and Django development, I see myself as an outstanding data driven, science oriented professional, experienced in large-scale social and environmental project development.

SKILLS

PORTUGUESE

MARKDOWN

PYTHON / DJANGO

MKDOCS

MKDOCS

MKDOCS

MKDOCS

BOOTSTRAP

SQL / POSTGRESQL

DATABASE DESIGN

FORM DESIGN

MS EXCEL

DATA COLLECTION

DATA WRANGLING

DATA CLEANSING

DATA ANALYSIS

DATA VISUALIZATION

AGILE / SCRUM

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 TO DATE - BUSINESS OWNER

Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil

QUADRAT CONSULTANCY AND SOCIOENVIRONMENTAL DEVELOPMENT LTD. — I've been working as a consultant since 2010, when I returned to Brazil from 5.5 years stay in the USA, mostly developing environmental impact assessment studies and analyzing their respective technical documentations. Along with this work I have been working on a few of my own web-based projects for the field, including a system to manage participatory public policy implementation, an online technical manual for best practices in urban trees management, and a service marketplace for the environmental sector of the economy.

2012 TO DATE - LEAD BIOLOGIST

Tres Coroas, RS, Brazil

CITY TOWN HALL OF TRES COROAS — As Lead Biologist I have been working extensively with environmental licensing, biodiversity management and urban trees management. Recently I have been working on a bioregional project (watershed based), developing a system to accommodate data pertaining to several smaller projects across 30 municipalities.

2005 - 2010 - RESEARCH ASSISTANT / ASSISTANT PROFESSOR

Melbourne, FL, USA

FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY — While pursuing my Ph.D., I have worked assisting research with **data collection, wrangling, cleansing and analysis for a mobile app** to help Alzheimer's caretakers, and for a nationwide environmental education assessment project. I have also taught University Experience, and Survey of Science for undergraduate students.

EDUCATION

1988 – 2002 UNIVERSITY OF THE SINOS RIVER VALLEY – UNISINOS

São Leopoldo, RS - Brazil

B. Sc. Biology (Graduate and Licensed Biologist)

Canoas, RS - Brazil

Master of Science Education for Sustainable Development

2005 - 2010 FLORIDA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY

2003 - 2005 LUTERAN UNIVERSITY OF BRAZIL - ULBRA

Melbourne, FL - USA

A.b.D. Environmental Education E.Ed. Interdisciplinary Studies

SOCIAL MEDIA







FOERMER EXPERIENCE

While as an academic, for half of my career I was a high school and college teacher working in private and public schools. During this time, I also taught computer programming (Basic and Logo languages). I have 20+ years of experience as an environmental consultant developing socioenvironmental projects.